Title,Event Type,Event Description,Arguments,Entities,Publish Date,URL
KP to launch polio drive on Dec 16 amid challenges,"emergency, declared, agreed","“More than 110 persons, including vaccinators and policemen guarding them during door-to-door campaigns have lost their lives to the bullets fired by unidentified people since 2012 due to which fear gripped the health workers and agreed to fake finger marking,” an official said. They added that the Emergency Operation Centre, which led anti-polio efforts in the province, was confronting a vicious cycle of refusals, missed children and fake finger marking.","{'Actor': ['Centre', 'Pakistan', 'Pakhtunkhwa', 'Chaudhry', 'Khan'], 'Action': ['declare', 'agree'], 'Target': ['funding', 'campaign', 'cycle', 'fingers', 'coordination', 'parents', 'challenges', 'poliomyelitis', 'resources', 'list', 'difference', 'refusal', 'drops', 'Dawn', 'children', 'wrath', 'efforts', 'infection', 'cases', 'virus', 'homes', 'pressure', 'them', 'administrations', 'lives', 'vaccination', 'marking', 'workers'], 'Location': ['Islamabad', 'Dawn', 'Nowshera', 'Balochistan', 'Pakistan', 'Khyber', 'Mohmand', 'Sindh', 'Pakhtunkhwa'], 'Time': ['2012', 'the', ',', 'current', 'year', '13th', '16', '2024', 'December', 'this']}","[('Khyber Pakhtunkhwa', 'PERSON'), ('around 7.3 million', 'CARDINAL'), ('44', 'CARDINAL'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('less than one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dawn', 'PERSON'), ('Pakistan', 'GPE'), ('59', 'CARDINAL'), ('this year', 'DATE'), ('26', 'CARDINAL'), ('Balochistan', 'GPE'), ('16', 'CARDINAL'), ('Khyber Pakhtunkhwa', 'GPE'), ('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sindh', 'GPE'), ('Punjab', 'NORP'), ('Islamabad', 'GPE'), ('Dera Ismail Khan', 'PERSON'), ('Khyber Pakhtunkhwa', 'ORG'), ('Ali Amin Gandapur', 'PERSON'), ('Faisal Karim Kundi', 'PERSON'), ('eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Lakki Marwat', 'PERSON'), ('Kohat', 'NORP'), ('Mohmand', 'GPE'), ('Nowshera', 'GPE'), ('the current year', 'DATE'), ('December 16', 'DATE'), ('More than 110', 'CARDINAL'), ('2012', 'DATE'), ('Nadeem Aslam Chaudhry', 'PERSON'), ('the Emergency Operation Centre', 'ORG'), ('Dawn', 'GPE'), ('December 13th, 2024', 'DATE')]",2024-12-13 09:11:50+05:00,https://www.dawn.com/news/1878485/kp-to-launch-polio-drive-on-dec-16-amid-challenges
"Senate unanimously passes National Forensic Agency Bill, 2024","introduced, passed, report","The Senate has unanimously passed the National Forensic Agency Bill, 2024 aimed at transforming the National Forensics Agency (NFA) project into an independent agency, APP reported on Friday. On Nov 8, the Senate Standing Committee on Interior passed the NFA bill which was introduced in the Senate by Interior Minister Mohsin Raza Naqvi on Oct 17.","{'Actor': ['Marri', 'Agency', 'Committee', 'APP', 'Senate', 'Tarar'], 'Action': ['introduce', 'pass'], 'Target': ['devices', 'NFA', 'NFCA', 'services', 'bill', 'laboratory', 'laws', 'challenges', 'Bill', 'Baltistan', 'Act', 'labs', 'amendments', 'control', 'lab', 'crimes', 'aid', 'project', 'forensics'], 'Location': ['Lahore', 'Kashmir'], 'Time': ['17', 'Nov', 'today', 'the', '2010', '8', 'Friday', 'hour', '2020', 'Oct', '2024']}","[('Senate', 'ORG'), ('the National Forensic Agency', 'ORG'), ('2024', 'DATE'), ('the National Forensics Agency', 'ORG'), ('APP', 'ORG'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('the National Forensics and Cybercrime Agency', 'ORG'), ('Nov 8', 'DATE'), ('the Senate Standing Committee on Interior', 'ORG'), ('NFA', 'ORG'), ('Senate', 'ORG'), ('Interior', 'ORG'), ('Mohsin Raza Naqvi', 'PERSON'), ('Oct 17', 'DATE'), ('Dawn.com', 'ORG'), ('The National Forensics Agency', 'ORG'), ('Law', 'PERSON'), ('Azam Nazeer Tarar', 'PERSON'), ('House', 'ORG'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('Gilgit-Baltistan', 'ORG'), ('Azad Jammu', 'PERSON'), ('Kashmir', 'LOC'), ('Lahore', 'GPE'), ('Shehbaz Sharif', 'PERSON'), ('2010', 'DATE'), ('the hour', 'TIME'), ('Marri', 'PERSON'), ('Zamir Hussain Ghumro', 'PERSON'), ('House', 'ORG'), ('Senate', 'ORG'), ('Senate', 'ORG'), ('Legal Aid and Justice Authority', 'ORG'), ('Bill', 'PERSON'), ('2024', 'DATE'), ('APP', 'ORG'), ('Tarar', 'PERSON'), ('the Legal Aid and Justice Authority Act', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('2020', 'DATE'), ('the Standing Committee', 'ORG'), ('House', 'ORG'), ('the standing committee', 'ORG'), ('Legal', 'ORG'), ('the Law Ministry', 'ORG'), ('the Ministry of Human Rights', 'ORG')]",2024-12-13 15:48:36+05:00,https://www.dawn.com/news/1878521/senate-unanimously-passes-national-forensic-agency-bill-2024
KP govt forms working group for climate change initiative,plan,"Besides, the TWG will also be responsible for developing a comprehensive climate change action plan for the province and serve as the central authority for integrating climate change adaptation and mitigation strategies into provincial polices.","{'Actor': ['Khan', 'Kamal', 'Gandapur', 'TWG'], 'Action': [], 'Target': ['contributions', 'ecosystems', 'leadership', 'initiatives', 'plan', 'sources', 'strategies', 'sectors', 'adaptation', 'mandate', 'projects', 'fund', 'province', 'convener', 'alignment', 'emissions', 'department', 'mechanisms', 'transfer', 'cooperation', 'group', 'policies', 'monitoring', 'programmes', 'partnerships', 'transparency', 'capabilities'], 'Location': ['Dera', 'Dawn', 'Kohat', 'Peshawar', 'KP'], 'Time': ['2024', ',', '12th', 'December']}","[('14', 'CARDINAL'), ('Faisal Amin Gandapur', 'PERSON'), ('the National Assembly', 'ORG'), ('Ali Amin Gandapur', 'PERSON'), ('TWG', 'ORG'), ('Prof Yasir Kamal', 'ORG'), ('the Environmental Protection Agency', 'ORG'), ('the Local Council Board', 'ORG'), ('the Peshawar Development Authority', 'ORG'), ('the Pakhtunkhwa Energy Development Organisation', 'ORG'), ('Dera', 'GPE'), ('Ismail Khan', 'PERSON'), ('Peshawar', 'ORG'), ('the Sustainable Energy and Economic Development Programme', 'ORG'), ('Shakeel Ahmad', 'PERSON'), ('Peshawar', 'GPE'), ('Mardan', 'PERSON'), ('Kohat', 'LOC'), ('GIZ', 'ORG'), ('Tahir Khan', 'PERSON'), ('TWG', 'ORG'), ('KP', 'GPE'), ('TWG', 'ORG'), ('TWG', 'ORG'), ('TWG', 'ORG'), ('TWG', 'ORG'), ('the environmental protection agency', 'ORG'), ('TWG', 'ORG'), ('Dawn', 'GPE'), ('December 12th, 2024', 'DATE')]",2024-12-12 07:05:14+05:00,https://www.dawn.com/news/1878176/kp-govt-forms-working-group-for-climate-change-initiative
"Amid ongoing digital law reforms, govt proposes new central cybercrime forensics agency",plan,"State minister for IT and Telecom Shaza Fatima Khawaja had confirmed the plan to “address concerns regarding misinformation”, saying that the amendments were under review.","{'Actor': ['Dawn', 'NFCA'], 'Action': [], 'Target': ['board', 'intelligence', 'weakness', 'NFCA', 'material', 'content', 'concerns', 'offices', 'news', 'laws', 'changes', 'plan', 'opinions', 'formation', 'amendments', 'technologies', 'person', 'agency', 'algorithms', 'deepfakes', 'support', 'use', 'cybercrime', 'department', 'crimes', 'offences', 'agencies', 'forensics', 'fraud'], 'Location': ['Islamabad', 'Kashmir', 'Shaza'], 'Time': ['earlier', 'years', 'week', 'A', 'seven', 'Thursday', 'day', 'Last', '2024']}","[('the National Forensics and Cybercrime Agency', 'ORG'), ('Dawn.com', 'ORG'), ('Thursday', 'DATE'), ('A day earlier', 'DATE'), ('seven years', 'DATE'), ('Last week', 'DATE'), ('Dawn', 'PERSON'), ('the Prevention of Electronic Crimes Act', 'ORG'), ('Shaza', 'GPE'), ('Fatima Khawaja', 'PERSON'), ('the NFCA Act', 'LAW'), ('2024', 'DATE'), ('Islamabad', 'GPE'), ('National Forensic Science Authority', 'ORG'), ('NFCA', 'ORG'), ('Islamabad Capital Territory', 'ORG'), ('Azad Jammu', 'PERSON'), ('Kashmir', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('NFCA', 'ORG'), ('Digital Rights Protection Authority', 'ORG'), ('the National Cyber Crime & Investigation Authority', 'ORG'), ('Inter-Services Intelligence, Military Intelligence', 'ORG'), ('Intelligence Bureau', 'ORG'), ('Islamabad', 'GPE'), ('AJK', 'ORG')]",2024-12-12 21:08:01+05:00,https://www.dawn.com/news/1878326/amid-ongoing-digital-law-reforms-govt-proposes-new-central-cybercrime-forensics-agency
